<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ana Rebelo</title>
    <link>https://anarebelo.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ana Rebelo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://anarebelo.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MINEX III Certification by NIST</title>
      <link>https://anarebelo.github.io/posts/minexiiienroll/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anarebelo.github.io/posts/minexiiienroll/</guid>
      <description>In collaboration with the Imprensa Nacional-Casa da Moeda (INCM), our work obtained MINEX III certification - Minutiae Interoperability Exchange - by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) of the United States (US) Department of Commerce. This certification is a test used to establish that template generation and correspondence algorithms comply with the US government&amp;rsquo;s Personal Identity Verification (PIV) program and aims to assess the quality and robustness of biometric recognition algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best reviewer award at IJCB2020</title>
      <link>https://anarebelo.github.io/posts/ijcb2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anarebelo.github.io/posts/ijcb2020/</guid>
      <description>The 2020 International Joint Conference on Biometrics (IJCB 2020) combines two major biometrics research conferences, the Biometrics Theory, Applications and Systems (BTAS) conference and the International Conference on Biometrics (ICB).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor in the Future of Computing Summer School.</title>
      <link>https://anarebelo.github.io/posts/foc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anarebelo.github.io/posts/foc/</guid>
      <description>Monitor in the GPU-Accelerated Computing workshop given by Cristiana Dinea from NVIDIA Deep Learning Institute. Check more at Future of Computing summer school website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creation of the SI-PSL database</title>
      <link>https://anarebelo.github.io/posts/si-psl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anarebelo.github.io/posts/si-psl/</guid>
      <description>Signer-Independent Portuguese Sign Language (SI-PSL) database The SI-PSL database was specially created for signer-independent evaluation purposes. It contains 31 isolated signs, representing the alphabet and the cardinal numbers 0 to 9 of the Portuguese sign language. All the signs were performed three times by a total of 11 native signers, in a free and natural signing environment, without any clothing restriction but with a slightly-controlled uniform background (see Figure below). Therefore, it clearly depicts the large inter-signer variability that exists in the manual signing process of sign languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creation of the CorSiL database</title>
      <link>https://anarebelo.github.io/posts/corsil/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anarebelo.github.io/posts/corsil/</guid>
      <description>A Portuguese Sign Language and Expressiveness Recognition Database The CorSiL database was created within the framework of a research project at INESC TEC, FEUP, Porto, Portugal, which aimed to develop both a video-based automatic SLR system and a expressiveness analysis method of the human body during the interaction between a pair of subjects. In this manner the CorSiL database has two major components (or subsets) each one with a specific purpose:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
